CV

Mads Hvelplund Grækenlandsvej 129 2300 København S, Danmark

Mobile: 50550272

E-mail: mhvelplund@gmail.com
LinkedIn: http://bit.ly/li_mhvelplund

Stack Overflow: http://bit.ly/so_mhvelplund



Introduction

I like the craft of software development, especially the process of understanding a complex business domain and reducing its problems to manageable chunks. My experience includes designing everything from individual features to complete platforms in domains from waste management to payment processing.

I have a strong background in Java, but I also have a good grasp of the .NET family of languages, and many modern JS frameworks.

On a personal level, I'm an extrovert and I get along well with people. I also enjoy learning from others and teaching them what I know.

Education

1995-2006: M.Sc. In Computer Science from DIKU, Copenhagen University

Industry experience

Financial (online payment), 4 yrs. Government (health), 2 yrs. Medical, 1 yrs. Waste Management, 1 yrs.

Work- and project experience

.NET department manager, Theilgaard Mortensen (May 2015 – December 2017)

.NET department manager

Role: Manager

Description:

I managed the .NET department, consisting of 3 consultants. My team delivered both ad hoc development at hourly rates and an in house developed electronic patient journal system used by the Danish Government.

As manager, my main focus was on improving the quality of deliveries on our EPJ product. I introduced code reviews and mandatory unit testing, and worked with support to standardize integration testing prior to releases.

Experience: Code review, Continuous Integration, Integration Testing, Unit Testing

Electronic patient journal system (EPJ)

Role: Architect, Team lead

Description:

I served as team lead and architect for the team that maintained TM's EPJ systems for child dental care, post-natal healthcare, and the Copenhagen dentist school. The child dental care system alone had more than half of the Danish municipalities with every child in them as customers. The back-end was Java based and the front-end was a C# WinForms application.

Experience: C#, EPJ, GEPJ, Java, VB.NET, Web services, WinForms

Self-service modules for EPJ system

Role: Systems Developer, Web Developer

Description:

I was the lead developer on the implementation of self-service modules for the EPJ system that integrated with NemLog-In.

Experience: Angular2, ASP.NET MVC, Bootstrap, C#, HTML5, Web services, OIOSAML.NET, SAML, SSO

Waste management portal

Role: Consultant, Systems Developer, Team Lead, Web Developer

Description:

I maintained waste management self-service portals for ISS and Novo Nordisk.

Experience: ASP.NET MVC, C#, HTML5, jQuery, MS Reporting Services, Web services

Quality control

Role: Architect, DevOps

Description:

I developed and introduced Docker/DropWizard middleware to ensure that only tested code would make it into the main product branches, and to link auto generated change logs with the issue tracking system.

Experience: CruiseControl.NET, Java, Jenkins, Docker, Drop Wizard, Target Process, Web services

Architectural review

Role: Architect, Systems Developer

Description:

I served as the main architect for most department projects, and I performed overhauls of the Java based back-end server's architecture, to replace homemade components with stock components from the Open Source community. The process helped reduce maintenance costs.

Experience: Bitronix JTA, Guava, Java, JAX-RS, Lombok, Web services

Log and server monitoring

Role: Architect, DevOps

Description:

I prototyped log- and server monitoring of our client solutions.

Experience: Docker, GrayLog, Nagios, NSClient, NXLog

Systems developer, Endomondo (January 2015 – April 2015)

Endomondo application back-end

Role: Systems Developer, Web Developer

Description:

I worked on the back-end used by the fitness app and the website during the transition from an Apache Wicket application to an OSGi/AngularJS solution deployed in AWS.

Experience: AngularJS, Apache Wicket, AWS, Java, OSGi, Web services

Unit testing

Role: Systems Developer

Description:

I rewrote the older parts of the backend to support unit testing.

Experience: JUnit, Mockito

Architect, DIBS (July 2010 – December 2014)

New Payment Gateway

Role: Architect, Team Lead, Systems Developer

Description:

I designed and prototyped a platform built around horizontally scalable servers deployed in Amazon's AWS cloud. The system used event sourcing and the CQRS pattern to share the load of processing payments, while simultaneously feeding a business back-end.

The final system was based on Axon CQRS and Redis, but during development both ActiveMQ and Riak where in play.

Experience: Apache ActiveMQ, Axon CQRS, AWS, MySQL, Redis, Riak, Spring, Web services

Server throttling **Role:** Architect

Description:

I designed, and helped implement, a configurable rate limiting proxy to during a hectic Christmas when the servers were buckling under the load. The system was conceived, developed and deployed over 48 hours, and was still in use 2 years later when I left.

Experience: Node.js, Redis, Web services

Systems developer, Eniro (March 2008 – June 2010)

Support tool

Role: Systems developer

Description:

I took responsibility for the in-house front-end used by the customer service department, streamlined the build process, and rewrote the application to use dynamic model binding.

Experience: Java, Java Webstart, Swing, Web services

Data integration

Role: Systems developer

Description:

I worked on the core data exchange collecting data from multiple sources and exporting them to the head office, providing data for both the websites and the print division.

Experience: Batch Processing, Java, J2EE 1.5, Web services

B2B master data portals

Role: Systems developer, Web developer

Description:

I worked on several portal sites for B2B projects for the Swedish head office.

Experience: Java, jQuery, Freemarker, OAuth 1.0, Spring, Web services

Consultant, Theilgaard Mortensen (March 2006 – February 2008)

Lotus Notes integration

Role: Systems developer, Web developer

Description:

I designed and developed an integration layer that allowed data from an external data warehouse for Business Denmark.

Experience: J2EE 1.5, Web services

Bogportalen and Gyldendals Bogklubber **Role:** Systems developer, Web developer

Description:

I developed e-commerce sites for a number of major Danish companies including Gyldendal.

Experience: J2EE 1.4, WebSphere Commerce, Web services

Work experience matrix

Level description:

- 1. I've worked with this, but I'm rusty
- 2. I can maintain existing solutions
- 3. I can work confidently from scratch or existing code
- 4. I can teach others
- 5. The subject is a core competence

Areas	Years	Last	Level
Architecture	6	2017	4
Back-end	11	2017	5
Consulting	4	2017	3
DevOps	2	2017	3
E-Commerce	2	2008	2
Frontend	7	2017	4
Government	2	2017	3
Open Source	11	2017	4
Payments (finance)	4	2014	3
Requirement Specification	6	2017	4
SOA	11	2017	5
System Design	6	2017	4
System Development	11	2017	4
System Integration	11	2017	5
Team Lead	6	2017	4
Waste Management	1	2017	2
Web Development	7	2017	4
Web Services	11	2017	5
Technologies	Years	Last	Level
.NET	2	2017	3
Ajax	7	2017	2
Amazon Web Services (AWS)	5	2016	3
Angular 2	2	2017	2
Apache ActiveMQ	2	2012	1
ASP.NET	2	2017	3
ASP.NET MVC	2	2017	3
Bootstrap	2	2014	1
C# (C-Sharp)	2	2017	3
Continuous Integration	7	2017	4
CruiseControl.NET	2	2017	5
Docker	4	2017	4
EPJ	2	2017	3

Technologies (cont.)	Years	Last	Level
FreeMarker	3	2012	2
HTML5	7	2017	3
IBM WebSphere Commerce	2	2008	1
Integration testing	7	2017	4
J2EE	4	2010	3
Java	11	2017	5
Java Swing	2	2010	3
JavaScript	7	2017	2
JAX-RS	2	2017	4
JAXB	4	2014	4
JBoss	3	2010	3
Jenkins	6	2017	4
jQuery	4	2014	2
JSON	6	2017	5
LINQ	2	2017	2
Linux	16	2017	3
Microsoft IIS	2	2017	3
Microsoft SQL Server	2	2017	1
MySQL	5	2015	4
Nagios	2	2017	3
Node.js	1	2012	2
Pull Requests	7	2017	5
Redis (database)	3	2014	3
REST	6	2017	5
Riak	2	2013	1
SAML	2	2017	4
Single sign-on (SSO)	2	2017	3
SOAP	10	2017	5
SoapUI	2	2014	4
Spring	5	2014	4
SQL	11	2017	4
Swagger	2	2017	5
Tomcat	11	2017	4
Unit Test	8	2017	5
VB.NET	2	2017	1
Web	11	2017	4
Web Services	11	2017	5
WinForms	2	2017	2
WSDL	10	2017	5